Abhilipsa Priyadarshini 🔾 Featured

Software Developer seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, XSLT, HTML, XML, MySQL, SVN, SQL, Python, Unix, RDBMS, JIRA, Agile, Scrum



Current Designation: Software Developer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Karmick Solutions Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: M.Tech [Computers]

Pref. Location: Kolkata, Ranchi, Bhubaneshwar

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project

Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Gap Analysis, Solution

Architecture, XSLT, HTML, XML, MySQL, SVN, SQL, Python, Unix, RDBMS, JIRA, Agile, Scrum

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

A dedicated and efficient software developer over 5 years of experience in coding and scripting in python in Django frame work.

Strong knowledge in EDI WTX map development for X12, EDIFACT, XML and CSV formats, AWS with IM, Php.

Both manual and automated testing knowledge in Unix environment (Integration Testing & Volume testing).

Familiar with cloud computing environments and its implementation. Exposure to SQL Queries.

Has worked with Agile methodology and familiar with scrum software development process and JIRA

Has proven ability to work well in a high-pressure environment, completed projects well before the deadlines and delighted the client with my work.

Has coordinated very well with different teams and delivered quality work faster

Work Experience

Karmick Solutions as Software Developer Nov 2020 to Till Date

Karmick Solutions as Software Developer May 2019 to Jul 2019

Programming and software: Python Code development

IDC Technologies as Application Support Admin Oct 2017 to May 2019

Client- Lupin Ltd.

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=ad70113fe59c3426f429cd06c2c3bcd90d5c0104491209160740470955...

Project-Lupin BIOVIA

Programming and software: Python, BIOVIA Application

Project Details:

We integrate the pharmaceutical instruments to a central application BIOVIA. It provides a scientific collaborative environment for advanced biological, chemical and materials experiences. It helps us to develop higher quality medicines faster and more cost effectively

We bring automation in all the laboratory manual work like analyzing, developing and testing of drugs and calibrating instruments

BIOVIA has multiple submodules and in the backend the coding for them are written in Python

Some of the codes are previously provided by BIOVIA we change them whenever requirement comes and for new module or for new instrument we write python codes

We closely work with scientists get the requirement, analyze them and start developing the module through python

Reduce the daily routine practices done by scientists through automation

The project used Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery(CICD)mechanism

Collaborating with multiple groups (LIMS, ELOG, BIOVIA etc.) for optimized solution

Responsibility: Technical Python coding and Scripting

Develop restful APIs using class based views in Python Django frame work

Section Template Design Bartender, User Management Review of new team member's tasks

Responsibility: Project Related

Task Prioritization

Weekly Status Report Preparation

Mentoring for New team members and enabling them technically and functionally for project works

Project Management

Developed and maintained implementation documentation.

Project- Lupin EDI

Programming and software: EDI WTX 8.3, ANT Script, SVN, Oracle 11g, SQL developer

Project Details:

Couple of us who are high performer are chosen to work on EDI project in parallel to BIOVIA project. Here our lead provides us some EDI Map development work where we develop using WTX tool

Responsibility: Technical

Requirement Analysis and logical map development by coordinating with client

EDI map development for EDIFACT, X12 and XML using WTX 8.3

Map Deployment through SVN and testing

Unit testing and Integration testing

Map failure Analysis

Review of new team member's tasks

Responsibility: Project Related

Weekly Status Report Preparation

Knowledge management by sharing new knowledge share emails to team and maintaining repository for future reference

Shreshta Info Global Services Pvt Ltd

Jun 2016 to Oct 2017

Project- CEVA EDI Logistics

Programming and software: EDI WTX Map Development, Python

Project Details:

Client was a logistics company (CEVA logistics) where we develop and maintain Python codes for small in-house applications

I also developed EDI map development for X12 and XML formats

Directly talk to overseas clients. Get the requirement and work on them

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from ramadevi womens autonomous college, bhubaneswar in 2008

PG: M.Tech (Computers) from Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology, KIIT Bhubaneswar in 2016

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

MCA

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
ITX 9.0, IBM WTX 8.3	
SVN, JIRA	
Python, XML/XSLT, HTML, SQL, MySql	
EDI, UNIX, RDBMS	
Agile, SCRUM	
pycharm, visual studio code	
Map Designer	
Windows7, Unix Sun Solaris	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time